<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl (Posts about plot-hook)</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/categories/plot-hook.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:noreply@blogger.com"&gt;Bujna Balázs&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:58:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Prefab housing estates in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/10/prefab-housing-estates-in-mage-budapest/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;span class="tooltip" title="The single outlier that breaks the pattern is the subject of another post."&gt;Thirty-one out of the city's 32&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;lakótelep&lt;/i&gt; [lɒkoːtɛlɛp], that is, housing estates (groups of prefabricated high-rises/low-rises with a patch or two of green in between them) are hives of pro-regime activity, and literal high-speed nodes in the agglomeration interwebs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="660" data-original-width="895" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/--Y_UKQTbezE/XYzR83r2bRI/AAAAAAAA13E/gJujtLKuhrEavZnHiDAKagYWbrya3mxbQCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/25806.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Status quo&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="545" data-original-width="600" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-PrEo2vDBYeE/XZJpaXtEZHI/AAAAAAAA13g/sQprnt7fYjEH1Vs4p1pY7KCPEOO7X8UDQCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/terkep-nagy-lakotelepek.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;The &lt;span class="tooltip" title="The high-rises are all taller in the setting than in real life, and accommodate more people."&gt;roughly 1 million people&lt;/span&gt; living in the city state tower blocks have consciously or subconsciously made a choice - in exchange for very tangible material and political benefits from the regime, they have accepted the requirements for living in a self-policed, paranoid gated community of sorts.&lt;br&gt;On the one hand the blocks themselves, the flats inside them, and every amenity and service that belongs to a &lt;i&gt;lakótelep&lt;/i&gt; are well-maintained and modernized by the councils (sometimes even beyond what their budget could afford, to the detriment of communities living beyond the high-rise perimeter) - think schools, libraries, swimming pools, street lighting, parks, drinking fountains, et cetera. (There's also talk of very high-quality drugs being much freely available than elsewhere in the city state.)&lt;br&gt;On the other hand there's a waiting list, and would-be home-owners are vetted for adherence to the governing party line, everyone is encouraged to spy on and report on their neighbours, people get arrested and frogmarched off the street and from cafés in broad daylight, inhabitants are ready to spray political insults on the cars and houses of those deemed disloyal in an attempt to look patriotic. They literally police themselves, usually overzealously.&lt;br&gt;So much so that it is an open secret that law enforcement is pretty much left to local neighbourhood watch groups, there's much less surveillance around, and locals typically pride themselves on the fact that they 'behave even when the masters aren't looking'. Ironically, this laissez-faire attitude is drawing dissenters to these areas (to conspire, subvert, or to be able to eat some of the best ice cream in town, and relax without being on camera), which, in turn, puts the local paramilitaries on high alert.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lakótelep internet&lt;/h2&gt;Housing estates in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl have the highest-speed internet in the land; the donwside is that it's only available in dedicated public spaces, never in people's homes (there might even be shielding or scrambling installed in places to prevent people from accessing the net in private), and that there are whole swaths of the web that can't be reached. Rumours of comment factories and paid internet troll armies operating out of one or more &lt;i&gt;lakótelep&lt;/i&gt;s abound.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt; 13 lakótelep [lɒkoːtɛlɛp] encounters&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;  &lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Pop-up open-air market. Home-grown (in basements and on rooftops) produce and stuff not available elsewhere in the city. Contraband? Authorities turning a blind eye?&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Group of enthusiastic activists handing out flyers/stickers. High-quality layout and design with motivational &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/05/the-szekeres-bara-life-system.html"&gt;Szekeres-Bara life system&lt;/a&gt; quotes, advertising some large public gathering (rally celebrating political anniversary, sports event, film screening, concert, etc.).&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Film shoot. Host of usually young extras milling about or being exhorted over PA, crowding onlookers.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Stopped and questioned by uniformed neighbourhood watch.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Rehearsal for large-scale musical number. Upbeat or marching music, acrobatic choreography, flowing fabrics of bright hues.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Over-zealous group from another &lt;i&gt;lakótelep&lt;/i&gt; come to even the odds in their favour in the upcoming Inter-lakótelep contest (sports and stuff like best-kept garden, cleanest street, most electric vehicles, quietest neighborhood) - spraying smear graffiti, beating up people, smashing cars.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Pro-government rally. Acting as though they were an oppressed minority.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Public meditation event in the park. The ubiquitous quasi-religious undertones of the &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/05/the-szekeres-bara-life-system.html"&gt;Szekeres-Bara worship of the self&lt;/a&gt;, with collective hallucinations, on account of augmented reality.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Overhaul of the wireless internet/fiber-optic cables in the block. Series of brief but migraine-inducing load tests.&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Staring. Innocuous, bored, or hostile.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;The dedication of a brand spanking new playground, library, building wing, swimming pool, park, free public internet hotspot, something really expensive and modern.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;FMajor car accident, possibly with fatalities, complete with vigilante lynch mob out to get revenge.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;    &lt;td class="numbercell"&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td&gt;Raucous rooftop party with strict no alcohol code but lots of interesting hallucinogens.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Plot hooks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A fire in a flat in one of the blocks of flats in the housing estate reveals secret compartment with mystickal books/portal/something of interest to the PC cabal, or evidence implicating one or more of the PCs in (terrorist?) plot.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PC is being cyber-bullied, scammed online, or their identity is stolen, and the clues lead into one of the hardline housing projects.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PCs learn of victim(s) of a gang who kidnap and torture loved ones to coerce back into the fold those who plan to leave the local Szekeres-Bara-esque, but radicalized cult.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The PCs' &lt;strike&gt;terrorist cell&lt;/strike&gt; cabal is planning to infiltrate and co-opt one of the housing project's popular associations. The plan is to slowly take over leadership, and gradually introduce their own agenda to &lt;strike&gt;brainwash the populace&lt;/strike&gt; spread the suppressed truth.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>location</category><category>plot-hook</category><category>random-table</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/10/prefab-housing-estates-in-mage-budapest/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 20:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Themes and Story Ideas</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/08/themes-and-story-ideas/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Some story/plot twist ideas to highlight the Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl themes [systemic corruption, social progress, magic, idealism, technology, apathy, treason/treachery, unity, rebellion, hopelessness, political dictatorship, disruptive DIY]:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="1067" data-original-width="1600" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8Mou8y7inmE/XVxRnGZ4a_I/AAAAAAAA11I/Ogz424oX8CQKr89hOLKiJJJBjlOmrc6OACLcBGAs/s320/ethan-hoover-cu1Yax4dDx4-unsplash.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="_3bJ2H CHExY"&gt;&lt;div class="_1l8RX _1ByhS"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@ethanchoover?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Ethan Hoover&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/search/photos/escalator?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PC mages start/help business (3D print shop, DIY freeze-dry, modelling agency for niche porn, automobile/mobile phone/implant repair shop, tattoo parlour, etc. Something appropriate for your high-tech/high-rise - low life/low-rent Eastern European post-communist setting). Soon, quasi-official paramilitary group indirectly enjoying the support of the government via a high-prestige government-funded non-for-profit organization show up, effectively demanding protection money in the form of some obscure tax. The tax is legit, turns out every single business is already paying, no two ways about it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGuffin: a list of high-ranking officials that a large construction firm has bribed. The government wants it, and might be willing to let the company operate in Budapest in exchange for the list and a hefty fine. Some radical mage group/non-mage group aided by mages wants to expose the list; they fear the government is going to make the list disappear once they get a hold of it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PCs witness a clandestine meeting between high-ranking mage (NPC from PCs' own org) and a &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-technocracy-magical-premise.html"&gt;Szövetkezet&lt;/a&gt; manager (on moving trams, hopping from one line to the next, mingling with crowds; accidentally spotted, quite difficult to follow, but actually conspicuous once PCs know what to look for). When PCs reveal their findings (to either party, or the media), one or both parties try bribing them, NPC claims acting "for the greater good".&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;False-flag operation: politician taken hostage, or mayor/priest/celebrity assassinated, or high-rise/public transport river boat station/tram/concourse in mall is blown up. PCs are either the perpetrators, acting on a request of higher-ups in their orgs, or involved as witnesses/investigators. The interesting bit is that clues are planted or asked to be planted that incriminate a specific other organization. Reprisals. Escalation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Smuggling people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PCs are political prisoners under house arrest, and they're the ones being smuggled out of their homes, quite unexpectedly and unbidden, by some shadowy org they have never heard of before. What's the agenda?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;There are strict border controls and immigration policies in place  (basically there is a maximum number of immigrants the city will take in  a year). PCs are involved in smuggling people into Budapest for profit.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PC smuggling ring is run on bribery.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PC smuggling ring is run in the Umbra - how do you cheat Paradox/Szövetkezet hackers on your trail?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Smuggling ring routinely involves shootouts with police, and explosions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PCs must whisk some out-of-town magical messenger across the city-wide blockade set up by protesters (The introduction of a new tax has been tabled in parliament, one that hits cyclists/smokers/drug-users/construction workers/health service staff/families of five or less people/etc. hard, and spontaneous resistance has sprung up. Budapest in deadlock for days now - no-one is allowed to cross the bridges and checkpoints except for ambulances and fire brigades.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;People are being made magically sick (via public transport system/fireworks/as part of a sham or real population census). The illness is a form of colour blindness where people have a hard time differentiating between various bank notes. This is doubly interesting for mages, given how frequent this particular affliction pops up as a Paradox flaw - now regular non-magical folks are getting it too. Heavily marketed new and expensive medication promises to cure the special form of colour blindness.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Appeasing the Budapest spirits. A series of accidents and sabotage at major construction site in city. Some &lt;span&gt;fin de siècle celebrity's (surely &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:20th-century_Hungarian_poets"&gt;a poet&lt;/a&gt; or an impresario) spirit or a building spirit (some crumbling or well-maintained &lt;a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/why-budapest-is-famous-for-its-art-nouveau-architecture-5982737"&gt;art nouveau mass&lt;/a&gt;) is annoyed with the reconstruction. What do you do?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;PCs find out that a certain group (redheads, AAA game developers, 8-bit ambient music fans, people with calligraphic prints or enamel pitchers/vinyl records/knives bought at &lt;a href="http://attractions.topbudapest.org/markets/ecseri-flea-market/"&gt;the Ecseri flea market&lt;/a&gt;) are being registered by the authorities. (Perhaps one of the PCs is also among those targeted.) Investigation reveals that the people in question share some mystical bond, and that plans are in place to lock these people up in underground internment camps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A massive &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/aug/13/worlds-largest-urban-farm-to-open-on-a-paris-rooftop"&gt;rooftop garden in the town centre&lt;/a&gt; is a major backdrop for scenes in the story: this is where an NPC always meets the PCs, or where some ransom is to be handed over, or shootout pursuit is staged, or one of the PCs lives in the building.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;A major NPC is moonlighting as a volunteer at an NGO helping the homeless.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>plot-hook</category><category>premise</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/08/themes-and-story-ideas/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hardytown, also known as Budapest District 5.</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/07/hardytown-also-known-as-budapest/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;In real life, Budapest has 23 districts, each with its distinct character.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;This is the first in a series of district write-ups for Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl that take advantage of the concept of &lt;a href="https://fate-srd.com/fate-core/extras#the-bronze-rule-aka-the-fate-fractal"&gt;the Fate fractal&lt;/a&gt; to give prospective Storytellers a potted bio or nutshell review of sorts.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="1600" data-original-width="1600" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IUdIqsA1HCI/XTYDsz7osrI/AAAAAAAA1yo/jU0gnQGR_UAO7UmeX6vuIX4Up0P_Egp7ACLcBGAs/s320/daniel-olah-RGeWvvLlEaA-unsplash.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@danesduet?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Daniel Olah&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/search/photos/budapest?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Location Aspects&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"Barcelona of the East"&lt;br&gt;This used to be THE City, and now it's an overpriced attraction overrun by boozing tourists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"Poster Child of the Regime"&lt;br&gt;Home of the city state government; every single experimental legislature, quietly ignored in less core areas, is in full force here - anyone in uniform is in their element over here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"The Mayor is King"&lt;br&gt;The long arms of Molnár [&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;ˈmolnaːr&lt;/span&gt;] the mayor, reach everywhere. It's an open secret that he's getting his beak wet in all sorts of local businesses, through a widespread network of fronts, stooges, and dummies, to be able to maintain his incorruptible public image.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Location Skills&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alertness: there are surveillance cameras everywhere, drones (some of them are flown by civilian-looking people, but you can never know, taxi drivers in the district are said to be on police payroll (if not outright clones, as some more paranoid willworkers will tell you). In short, &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;the system of public trust&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; ("közbizalom" [&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;ˈkøz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;&lt;span class="ipa"&gt;ˌ&lt;/span&gt;bizɒlom&lt;/span&gt;]) set out by the powers that be - part Social Credit System, part Big Society - is in full swing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;Watch &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jm8TKf0eTEs"&gt;this eye-opening discussion&lt;/a&gt; about what the Social Credit System looks like from the inside.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Resources: people living here, and people staying here, are rich. Everything is fancier, and there are more pickpockets, and more con artists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Security: It is virtually impossible to make a clean getaway once the authorities have been alerted to some subversive shenanigans of a PC or his posse.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Point of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;The historic (outer) city walls (from the 15. century). Most of it demolished, some of it maintained or reconstructed as a listed building. All of still magickal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="853" data-original-width="1280" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GIeCAL3D2ko/XTYLrKahviI/AAAAAAAA1y0/gFWmZzGqVRwtBhi67wbl8whBDcIgLMgvACLcBGAs/s320/85e242eb4dd69d1397402e421164c5a1.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let's go whole hog with the Bronze Rule, and give this POI a set of Fate aspects and skills as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;City Wall Aspects&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="500" data-original-width="1000" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-rF5ynO5k_Kg/XTYYVXZ0WmI/AAAAAAAA1zA/aqAOEJcSAwAgLtpq12pn7LGh_Sw9HhNTgCLcBGAs/s320/160693_pest_nyito.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;"I've got the highest-value real-estate in the city state."&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Secrets for sale.&lt;br&gt;(Can be 'interrogated' as a witness, if the 'interrogator' does not think asking a wall questions silly.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extends underground in parts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A mind of its own.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt; City Wall Skills&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="380" data-original-width="550" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XumzpmroQ-o/XTYYbZ6NiqI/AAAAAAAA1zE/G053g7E6D6EQu2kQF9ze-6OCDcWqNq8wwCLcBGAs/s320/pest10.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;City Wall gates (there's 4 of them, numbered in the diagram below - basically wide streets leading within the historically enclosed space) have&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the &lt;b&gt;Bureaucracy&lt;/b&gt; skill that they use to demand payment (mystical or otherwise) from those wishing to enter,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Alertness&lt;/b&gt;/&lt;b&gt;Scan&lt;/b&gt;, that they use to take note of anyone entering and exiting - a bit like having some mystical security cameras that a mage with the necessary skill may take advantage of.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;City Wall Stunts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="419" data-original-width="550" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ONjRn4kkA88/XTYY0nD1NBI/AAAAAAAA1zQ/VAK9OWUUVawffEqsfGkvoUWEKc4pxYewwCLcBGAs/s320/pestrajzok0.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Willworkers whose paradigm is consistent with an historic, physically not quite existing wall having mystic power-ons, the City Wall offers the following:&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Teleportation along perimeter.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The mystic shadow of the wall can hide mages from scrying attempts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;NPC&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="1024" data-original-width="1024" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-GVedMv7I6k0/XTt1sPKeFjI/AAAAAAAA1zo/DUodftP0xaoJlabcNWKgs6sch75_k6M1wCLcBGAs/s320/molnar.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Molnár, the mayor since forever. He is the main employer for people living in the district, directly or indirectly, through shell companies. Very many people's livelihood depends on not getting on his wrong side. To be fair, there are countless projects he's introduced, organizing street fairs, promoting businesses (the 'right' ones), offering aid to old age pensioners and youth, building and maintaining playgrounds, all the sorts of things people expect from a mayor. He's popular, then; people grumble, but vote for him time and again.&lt;br&gt;GMs might equally make him out to be either a sinister figure (that is, a Szövetkezet technocrat or someone influenced by a Syndicate advisor), or a well-meaning man-of-the-people corrupted and turned into little more than a mobster by power.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Plot hook&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nasty-looking, extremely ripe mangoes turn up at fire-sale prices in recently opened outlet of supermarket chain that was hyped in all the local media. Turns out the things are some sort of Umbrood eggs(?).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improbable traffic recorded/reported at one or more City Wall gates - the same person entering several gates at once, entering walls but never exiting, and/or exiting without having first entered.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>location</category><category>NPC</category><category>plot-hook</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/07/hardytown-also-known-as-budapest/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 23:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Water Tower High-Rise</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/06/the-water-tower-high-rise/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the tallest tower block has awakened in Budapest's District 15 (Újpalota &lt;span class="IPA"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;ˈuːj&lt;/span&gt;ˈpɒlotɒ], &lt;/span&gt;although many local Szekeres-Bara practitioners now routinely call it &lt;i&gt;Clear City&lt;/i&gt;. very Budapest district has been semi-officially been re-christened to reflect some benefit or tenet of the Szekeres-Bara movement; the pattern is '&lt;i&gt;&amp;lt;unique-name&amp;gt; City|Town&lt;/i&gt;'), which is mostly one big prefab housing project with patches of greenery.&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="800" data-original-width="449" height="320" src="https://m.blog.hu/ha/hazakbanjartunk/image/wp_20150207_15_44_34_pro.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;It was originally built as a water tower to boost water pressure in the housing estate that mushroomed around it a few decades ago (hence the name &lt;i&gt;Water Tower High-Rise&lt;/i&gt;) - have a look at &lt;a href="https://hazakbanjartunk.blog.hu/2015/02/19/ujpalotai_viztoronyhaz"&gt;lots of photos, floor plan, and section plans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="616" data-original-width="1376" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BJcWEpfpBuA/XO_ownHDzRI/AAAAAAAA1tI/pewVO1rLF7wdYaV6XOo3iJFMukA8bW6LACLcBGAs/s320/Ujpalota.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Then, the fateful decision was made to pull up a residential high-rise around the tower with the huge tank at the top.&lt;br&gt;Perhaps it was the unfamiliar presence of all those bodies and minds around it; first the builders, then the families moving in? Perhaps it was the building technology, quite unique in the district (the building is actually not a prefab at all)? Perhaps it was that the high-rise was meant to be the iconic symbol of the district, and the intention was a success beyond the city planners' wildest dreams? However it happened, the building's spirit woke up.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Personality &lt;/h2&gt;It has, from Day 1, considered itself a sort of guardian or mother figure&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;to its 'little siblings', that is, the bunches of 10-story prefabs that stream out from its hub like the spokes of a wheel,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;to the tiny little people with the exotic little consciousness-blobs hanging around them,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;to the trees, playgrounds, statues&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;After all, it had been its duty to supply nurturing, cleaning, refreshing, sustaining drinking water to most of them. (The building was a functioning water tower for only ten years after being erected.)&lt;br&gt;In exchange for favours, the tower spirit always asks for some quest to be undertaken to help the district in a specific or general way - clean up park, replace lock, make crossing in front of kindergarten safe, find key/pet parrot/lost cat and return it to owner, prevent suicide, prevent local branch of library from getting cut from next year's budget, etc.&lt;br&gt;However, to this day the water pipes act as a surveillance network of sorts through which the Water Tower High-Rise has psychic access to a surprisingly large proportion of the district's built environment - the specifics of this link is left to Storyteller discretion.&lt;br&gt;What is certain, however, is that to make use of the effect, a mage needs to enter the former cisterns at the very top of the tower, either physically, or in the Penumbra.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gate-keeper&lt;/h2&gt;The erstwhile cisterns have been remodelled into two large studio flats, inside one of which lives, rent-free, Harsányi (&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;ˈhɒrʃaːɲ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;]), the council-sponsored caretaker of the high-rise. He's joint building manager, condominium representative, janitor, and snitch for the Szövetkezet (the local Syndicate-flavour Technocratic upstarts), all rolled into one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;He's a spineless and petty yes-man, but also a practising chess champion - he can get really passionate and nerdy about his hobby, which the only aspect of his life not dominated by council rules and regulations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;Should PC wizards want to get inside the ex-tanks (to commit some &lt;strike&gt;terrorist&lt;/strike&gt; counter-revolutionary attack, or ask the tower spirit some questions about the district goings-on, perhaps), they will find that Harsányi's chess obsession has created a bubble of local consensus aggressively hostile towards those of the willworker persuasion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><category>location</category><category>NPC</category><category>plot-hook</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/06/the-water-tower-high-rise/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 22:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Batthyány Circle - Traditionalist faction in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl, part 4</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-batthyanyi-circle-traditionalist/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the last part in a series of high-level overviews of the 4 main Traditionalist factions in my Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl campaign.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Batthyány Circle&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="600" data-original-width="800" height="240" src="https://1.kerulet.ittlakunk.hu/files/ittlakunk/styles/large/public/upload/company/1256/batthyany_teri_vasarcsarnok7_ady_egykor.hu_.jpg?itok=m1ZMHEyB"&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Batthyány Market Hall's iconic clock&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a highly secretive and close-knit cabal centred around a magical contraption that generates Bitcoin or some equivalent cryptocurrency.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Suri&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="540" data-original-width="600" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8uulW9RgW2s/XMRr0WUgN0I/AAAAAAAA1lM/Zc-1ieKeplky2G-dSUniqALVKIHUCIeXgCLcBGAs/s320/attractive-beautiful-beautiful-woman-1895161.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="level__left"&gt;&lt;div class="level__item"&gt;&lt;div class="js-copy-attribute-content rd__p rd__p--no-margin"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/@charry-jin-921439?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Charry Jin&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/bald-woman-touching-clear-glass-window-1895161/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;An opportunistic ascetic.&lt;br&gt;The bartender at the collective's market hall coffee shop - the public face of the group, at least the mundane public face.&lt;br&gt;She craves power, and she's milking Hanifa's infatuation with her for all its worth - not much, though, to be honest.&lt;br&gt;She knows Sebestyén Aba from childhood, they've been kidnapped and held for some time - by whom, where, and why, has never been established.&lt;br&gt;Though she isn't too hot about her, she does acknowledge Hanifa as her mentor and magickal teacher - in fact, many of her rotes require the presence and active collaboration of both Hanifa and Suri.&lt;br&gt;Miranda, she feels, is the only sane person around her, but it seems her friendship is hard to earn. &lt;br&gt;She's torn between being a wallflower and taking the limelight.&lt;br&gt;She feels she's destined for larger things than some petty and doomed resistance, as she sees it, but Hanifa doesn't think that she's ready to go it alone yet - if ever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hanifa &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="400" data-original-width="600" height="213" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y-BGkTn2jqw/XMRuu28ej9I/AAAAAAAA1lo/L4i7k7W-3hwX7242cHsiCTcGzZYDXTyAwCLcBGAs/s320/hanifa.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Resistance guerilla, the leader of the collective.&lt;br&gt;She wants to build up a community, of wizards, lesbians, resistance fighters - whatever would work for her.&lt;br&gt;In love, perhaps too much so, with Suri, her student and protégé. The feeling isn't mutual, as she sometimes does admit to herself.&lt;br&gt;Sebestyén Aba is in fact her son, but she feels he's much too frivolous and hollow to be given the second-in-command status in the collective, or even to be left alone to his devices. It pains her that Sebestyén, for his part, is ashamed of her mum's to him grotesque magick and ways.&lt;br&gt;She saved Miranda's life, an accident, really, which is how they've met and decided to strike out as business partners.&lt;br&gt;She hopes Miranda's smallish network of sales acquaintances will somehow generate some mainstream appeal for her beliefs, and get that community going. It's a long shot. &lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sebestyén Aba&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="735" data-original-width="600" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aO2ujJjrM74/XMRt49elprI/AAAAAAAA1lY/7MhTG47wYjs-VOPVptUz_1UGokhTOPgMgCLcBGAs/s320/sebestyen.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Flaneur chaos wizard.&lt;br&gt;The whole business, and and Hanifa's plans to topple the Syndicate's economic stranglehold over Budapest hinges on his cryptocurrency-generator, his own invention.&lt;br&gt;It's acceptance that he craves from his environment, even if his carefully groomed exterior is that of a well-dressed, work-shy wiseguy who sidesteps society’s rules to live as he pleases.&lt;br&gt;He's torn between his well-hidden inhibitions and his artistic ambitions as a celebrated street photographer.&lt;br&gt;He's ashamed of his mother, Hanifa, for ignoring their aristocratic heritage - he isn't going to make that mistake.&lt;br&gt;Miranda is his wife, who desires him viscerally, but whom he more or less ignores because he feels she's beneath her. It's a marriage of convenience.&lt;br&gt;He and Suri were kidnapped and held in some basement for a time - he doesn't remember much save for the darkness, the blinding lights that sometimes broke that darkness, and the pain. Perhaps they've been experimented on, but what matters more is that he has been in love with Suri ever since. Suri is a coy tease, and apparently hasn't yet made up his mind about whether to enter into an affair - any way, it will end badly for Sebestyén, a fact he's blissfully unaware of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt; Miranda&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="715" data-original-width="600" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S_3mFrSZfk0/XMRuKsNZnwI/AAAAAAAA1lg/ALhkBxHJHFMCg_SAYUjrhZ4k3drPHSH7QCLcBGAs/s320/miranda.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="level__left"&gt;&lt;div class="level__item"&gt;&lt;div class="js-copy-attribute-content rd__p rd__p--no-margin"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/@oleg-magni?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Oleg Magni&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/portrait-of-curly-haired-girl-918474/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whimsical New Age witch.&lt;br&gt;Recovered alcoholic, driven to suicide that Hanifa prevented, has been immensely grateful ever since, now that they've become business partners with her mother-in-law, she's not so sure.&lt;br&gt;What she wants more than anything is comfort and calm, but her life is still quite tumultuous, what with the husband who has eyes for the stunning and impassive bartender, and her coffee shop being taken over for spreading anti-establishment propaganda. I guess she's the sort of person who always wants to take charge of her life but relies on others too much to pull it off.&lt;br&gt;She's a bit taken aback by Suri's advances - does she really think she would be best buddies with the chick her husband wants to bang instead of her? When she stays faithful even when she could have any man (true, she does have a sort of magnetism)?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>faction</category><category>NPC</category><category>plot-hook</category><category>premise</category><category>traditionalist magick</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-batthyanyi-circle-traditionalist/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl Dramasystem Series Pitch</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/a-mage-budapest-urbancrawl-dramasystem/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to write up the setting as a &lt;a href="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2012/10/hillfolk-dramasystem-rpgs-i-like.html"&gt;Dramasystem&lt;/a&gt; series pitch. I have two reasons.&lt;br&gt;On the one hand, I would definitely do character generation (at least!) for any campaign in the setting using Dramasystem guidelines, and I would recommend it to anyone (I sadly wasn't yet aware of Robin D. Laws' system when I started with the present group.)&lt;br&gt;On the other hand, I feel formulating the setting in as many formats as I can certainly helps to get it across, so here goes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="1200" data-original-width="1600" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Q3v29XafSHw/XLnQyt1AkhI/AAAAAAAA1jw/1yBhcQpbefAebqYHHXTtXO0e442F7_fkACLcBGAs/s320/richard-bohus-762727-unsplash.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/yZDATZKDoOo?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Richard Bohus&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/@briczi?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Group of mages deal with infighting, and intrigue between their peer groups while surviving in an urban fantasy version of contemporary Budapest that is in many ways geared against magic-users.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Setting&lt;/h2&gt; I've already detailed the history of the setting &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-technocracy-magical-premise.html"&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Andrássy Rifts&lt;/h3&gt; There's &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/the-andrassy-rifts-magical-premise.html"&gt;a previous post all about this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;Paradox in this setting is the metaphor for the unease,  hostility, and discrimination that mages elicit from non-magickal  society, and the system that is in control of that society.&lt;br&gt;To  bring this home fully, Paradox flaws and backlashes in this setting  tends to manifest as socially frowned-upon or debilitating conditions  such as stammering, epileptic seizure, motor impairment in limbs,  blindness or extreme myopia, facial scarring, etc.&lt;br&gt;Alternately, there could even exist a sort of 'wizards disease' such as color blindness, as a form of permanent paradox that afflicts all magickal people, and is a stigma: the basis of slurs and discrimination (so that, for example, mages have trouble differentiating between various banknotes without using magickal means).&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Szekeres-Bara Theory of Self&lt;/h3&gt;(disclaimer: I'm still struggling with this component of the setting - I feel I need a sort of scam religion to justify and lend moral superiority to the establishment, but it seems coming up with a workable concept that fits the setting is more than I bargained for) &lt;br&gt;This is a state-sponsored and -endorsed human potential movement self-religion along the lines of Scientology, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arica_School"&gt;Arica&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erhard_Seminars_Training"&gt;est&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fourth_Way"&gt;Gurdjieff School&lt;/a&gt;, and the like.&lt;br&gt;Detailed write-up planned!&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Setting questions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How widespread and intense is this repression really? (Does it resemble in any way, shape, or form &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-45474279"&gt;the way Uighurs are treated in China&lt;/a&gt;?)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do magickal people have to register? Are they prevented (in a magickal way disguised as technology) from entering certain areas?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;is there a secret police?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How ubiquitous is the propaganda machine?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is there a police state?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do mages have a person, symbol, or artifact to serve as the icon of their rebellion (like early Christians had the fish symbol)?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How advanced is the technology?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How bleak and cyberpunk is the world?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are Technocratic agents a playable option?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is the Technocracy irredeemably evil, are Technocrats just mistaken, or is the Technocracy also (if less enthusiastically and/or openly) fighting against the Powers that Be that they've helped set up but which has since outgrown them and their control?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are the Traditionalist/Disparate factions really a scourge to rid society of - are the PCs righteously resisting rebels, or deluded terrorists?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Characters&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sample Roles&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cabal Leader: probably has some dark secret - no-one can become an influencer with this recent history without having at least one unsavoury compromise in their past. Possibly also has dirt on one or more of his peers to keep them sweet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Firebrand: possibly personally traumatised by the Technocracy (family disappeared, ambitions thwarted, blacklisted, imprisoned, etc.) and now seeking revenge; has only these milquetoast cabal-mates to rely on.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rookie: has just awakened and been recruited to the cabal - still has trouble adjusting to being on the receiving end of all the unconscious discrimination that he's dished out as a 'normal' in his now-past life.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Technocracy Spy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acolyte: non-magickal sympathizer of the wizards' cause.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tourist Mage: came for the party, stayed for the party/The Party/Love/Ascension/War/?. An outcast within outcasts - Budapest mages on the whole don't take too kindly to outsiders.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cabal Lieutenant: keeping the troops happy while vying for his boss's position.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Specialist: an magickal academic/experimenter who couldn't care less about their social environment. Only interested in Ascension/on the cusp of a major breakthrough/etc.; a liability to the cabal as far as security and PR goes, but can they afford to let the Specialist go and die alone, or be recruited by another faction?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Martyr: the 'normals' need to know about the nature of reality even if they mock us as we try to teach them about it. Probably alone with such views within the cabal.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Character build questions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;How many of you are there in your cabal? What are the points of friction within the group?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How well do you feel your paradigm/Tradition/magickal support group is represented within the Budapest agglomeration?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What is your opinion of the so-called "tourist mages" who come to fill up on all the Quintessence flowing about and then either settle or move on?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What do you think of the relatively large Chinese community in Budapest? &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In what way do you personally feel marginalized in Budapest?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What is your stance towards the Andrássy Rifts? Are they an opportunity or a source of danger to Budapest?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How important is Ascension in your life?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How important is your non-magickal family (if you have any non-magickal family) in your life?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;Francesco Rosi films, such as Cadaveri Eccelenti.&lt;br&gt;&lt;iframe width="600" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9eONvq0kAbo" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Survival &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Civil War&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;(Anti-)Terrorism &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Corruption Eats Your Soul&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Resistance&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trying for a Second Chance on a Missed Opportunity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Injustice &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Treading Water&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Paranoia&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hope&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sense of Exclusion&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We Can Do This, We Don't Need Anyone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dog Eat Dog&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tightening the Screws&lt;/h2&gt;Here's where &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/goals-and-obstacles-implied-by-premise.html"&gt;the Dark Secrets&lt;/a&gt; come in.&lt;br&gt;Throw them at your players when they seem to settle into a rut. &lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Names&lt;/h2&gt;Hungarian or Chinese family names.&lt;br&gt;Everyone is known only by their family name or "handle". Perhaps even official records only contain a single name for people, with some other biometric data identifying people with the same name. &lt;br&gt;Ádám, Bedics, Li, Csiszár, Kovács, Tóth, Nagy, Fekete, Magyar, Chen, Takács, Hegedűs, N. Bodnár, Somogyi 2., Zhang, Zhao, Sárossy, Treuer</description><category>about</category><category>dramasystem</category><category>plot-hook</category><category>premise</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/a-mage-budapest-urbancrawl-dramasystem/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Rudas Thermal Baths - Location, NPC, Plot Hooks</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-rudas-thermal-baths-location-npc/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;a href="http://en.rudasfurdo.hu/"&gt;Rudas Baths (pronounced something like "Roux Dosh" ([ˈrudɒʃ]))&lt;/a&gt; is one of the Turkish-style bath houses in Budapest.&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://i1.wp.com/welovebudapest.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/07/Rudas-Fu%CC%88rdo%CC%8B_Bo%CC%81dis-Krisztia%CC%81n_006.jpg?resize=1200%2C720&amp;amp;ssl=1" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="480" data-original-width="800" height="192" src="https://i1.wp.com/welovebudapest.com/en/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2017/07/Rudas-Fu%CC%88rdo%CC%8B_Bo%CC%81dis-Krisztia%CC%81n_006.jpg?resize=1200%2C720&amp;amp;ssl=1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;In the M:TBU setting, it is a location much like &lt;a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Digital_Web_(book)"&gt;the Spy's Demise BBS detailed in Digital Web&lt;/a&gt;: perhaps the only place in town where the Awakened and Enlightened of any stripe can come together and talk without fear of aggression. By mutual agreement, Technocrats and Traditionalist, hell, even upstart Disparates, can rub shoulders here and chat.&lt;br&gt;How is that possible?&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt; The waters of  the Rudas Thermal Bath are heavily &lt;a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Prime_(MTAs)"&gt;Prime-infused&lt;/a&gt; and serves as the basis of an implicit truce - no need to fight when there's plenty of the good stuff for everyone.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h4&gt;The Baths are ideal for making plans, diplomatic encounters, trying to ferret out the enemies plans, subtle backstabbing, building up or losing face, or just to lay back &amp;amp; soak up Quintessence in wondrous environment.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h4&gt; &lt;/h4&gt;&lt;h4&gt;I like to play up the intoxicating nature of this  naturally-occurring Quintessence so that getting wet is like having a  few beers. You get giddy if you save your saving throw.&lt;/h4&gt;(Mechanically, I give everyone who stays at least an hour in the water d10/2 temporary Quintessence - they only find out how much when they leave, and it's lost if not used up within 24 hours. That's not a tamper proof rule, but what is?)&lt;br&gt;The explanation is that there's a Horizon node with a portal somewhere inside &lt;a href="https://welovebudapest.com/en/venue/gellert-hill-2/"&gt;Gellért Hill&lt;/a&gt;, where the magickal water springs from. Its location is a secret guarded from everyone, including their Traditionalist peers, by &lt;span class="tooltip" title="To be covered in a future post."&gt;the Monkey King Collective,&lt;/span&gt; a small cabal of semi-rogue Budapest mages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h4&gt;If the spring fell into the wrong hands, the fallout would be devastating.&lt;/h4&gt;Though the Technocracy pays lip-service to the agreement that everyone has equal rights to the magick water, they still keep trying to covertly find the Rudas Node - and some would say every single other faction is after the Node too. &lt;a href="https://www.xpatloop.com/channels/2018/09/gellert-hill-funicular-under-construction.html"&gt;There is a funicular secretly being built that would carve into the side of the hill&lt;/a&gt; - it's an open secret that this is a smokescreen to cover the search for the Node, but no-one is sure who is behind the project.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;NPC&lt;/h1&gt;Everyone who's been to the place more than twice knows Béla (&lt;span class="st"&gt;[ˈbeːlɒ]) (and he will definitely know regulars by name), the affable if moody locker room attendant who some think might be &lt;a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Extraordinary_Citizen"&gt;an Extraordinary Citizen&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.dmsguild.com/product_info.php?products_id=19&amp;amp;it=1&amp;amp;language=es&amp;amp;"&gt;a consor&lt;/a&gt;. The amount of magickal activity he must have been exposed to in his decades on the job could have affected him, but others think he's actually 'repelling magick and/or Paradox', arguing that he couldn't have survived. Anyways, he's a talking point among bath patrons - an ice-breaker when at a loss for what to say.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class="st"&gt;He's got a no-nonsense attitude and never gets fazed by anything - he sure acts like he's seen it all.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;table class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="480" data-original-width="800" height="192" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2019/02/19/16/10005514-6720971-image-a-7_1550595563042.jpg"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Béla, locker room attendant&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;He could be a fixer, a concierge, a messenger, a procurer of under-the-counter goods and/or a fountainhead of gossip for your PCs.&lt;br&gt;In my game he's a decidedly non-magickal ex-con who's got the cushy job in exchange for regular reports to &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-technocracy-magical-premise.html"&gt;the people in the Szabadság Square bunkers&lt;/a&gt;. His job description includes turning a blind eye to the shenanigans of mages high on Quintessence, and taking notes, but he likes bribes, and anyone who helps his daughter (a stunning and bubbly ballerina who tends to get mixed up in trouble) has a place in his heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Plot Hook&lt;/h1&gt;These are variations on "protect the water", but there's always the Nephandus plot that subtly taints the water to cause strife and overdoses.&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Magick is no protection against encroaching bureaucracy - council plans to shut down the place temporarily or to modify its water source (!) must be stopped by hook or by crook. Legal, illegal, or magickal.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The bath-house is being renovated, and builders find a Wonder or a portal (could it be the sought-after link to the Node?). Technocrats and Mages need to band together to overcome the inevitable pointing of fingers and point-scoring to hush up the discovery.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The water starts to ebb. What's up? Foul play in Budapest, or some trouble over at the Horizon end?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><category>location</category><category>NPC</category><category>plot-hook</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-rudas-thermal-baths-location-npc/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 21:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>