<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl (Posts about traditionalist magick)</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/categories/traditionalist-magick.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:noreply@blogger.com"&gt;Bujna Balázs&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 14:58:55 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The Batthyány Circle - Traditionalist faction in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl, part 4</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-batthyanyi-circle-traditionalist/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is the last part in a series of high-level overviews of the 4 main Traditionalist factions in my Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl campaign.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Batthyány Circle&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="600" data-original-width="800" height="240" src="https://1.kerulet.ittlakunk.hu/files/ittlakunk/styles/large/public/upload/company/1256/batthyany_teri_vasarcsarnok7_ady_egykor.hu_.jpg?itok=m1ZMHEyB"&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Batthyány Market Hall's iconic clock&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a highly secretive and close-knit cabal centred around a magical contraption that generates Bitcoin or some equivalent cryptocurrency.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Suri&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="540" data-original-width="600" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8uulW9RgW2s/XMRr0WUgN0I/AAAAAAAA1lM/Zc-1ieKeplky2G-dSUniqALVKIHUCIeXgCLcBGAs/s320/attractive-beautiful-beautiful-woman-1895161.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="level__left"&gt;&lt;div class="level__item"&gt;&lt;div class="js-copy-attribute-content rd__p rd__p--no-margin"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/@charry-jin-921439?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Charry Jin&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/bald-woman-touching-clear-glass-window-1895161/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;An opportunistic ascetic.&lt;br&gt;The bartender at the collective's market hall coffee shop - the public face of the group, at least the mundane public face.&lt;br&gt;She craves power, and she's milking Hanifa's infatuation with her for all its worth - not much, though, to be honest.&lt;br&gt;She knows Sebestyén Aba from childhood, they've been kidnapped and held for some time - by whom, where, and why, has never been established.&lt;br&gt;Though she isn't too hot about her, she does acknowledge Hanifa as her mentor and magickal teacher - in fact, many of her rotes require the presence and active collaboration of both Hanifa and Suri.&lt;br&gt;Miranda, she feels, is the only sane person around her, but it seems her friendship is hard to earn. &lt;br&gt;She's torn between being a wallflower and taking the limelight.&lt;br&gt;She feels she's destined for larger things than some petty and doomed resistance, as she sees it, but Hanifa doesn't think that she's ready to go it alone yet - if ever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Hanifa &lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="400" data-original-width="600" height="213" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Y-BGkTn2jqw/XMRuu28ej9I/AAAAAAAA1lo/L4i7k7W-3hwX7242cHsiCTcGzZYDXTyAwCLcBGAs/s320/hanifa.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Resistance guerilla, the leader of the collective.&lt;br&gt;She wants to build up a community, of wizards, lesbians, resistance fighters - whatever would work for her.&lt;br&gt;In love, perhaps too much so, with Suri, her student and protégé. The feeling isn't mutual, as she sometimes does admit to herself.&lt;br&gt;Sebestyén Aba is in fact her son, but she feels he's much too frivolous and hollow to be given the second-in-command status in the collective, or even to be left alone to his devices. It pains her that Sebestyén, for his part, is ashamed of her mum's to him grotesque magick and ways.&lt;br&gt;She saved Miranda's life, an accident, really, which is how they've met and decided to strike out as business partners.&lt;br&gt;She hopes Miranda's smallish network of sales acquaintances will somehow generate some mainstream appeal for her beliefs, and get that community going. It's a long shot. &lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sebestyén Aba&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="735" data-original-width="600" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aO2ujJjrM74/XMRt49elprI/AAAAAAAA1lY/7MhTG47wYjs-VOPVptUz_1UGokhTOPgMgCLcBGAs/s320/sebestyen.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Flaneur chaos wizard.&lt;br&gt;The whole business, and and Hanifa's plans to topple the Syndicate's economic stranglehold over Budapest hinges on his cryptocurrency-generator, his own invention.&lt;br&gt;It's acceptance that he craves from his environment, even if his carefully groomed exterior is that of a well-dressed, work-shy wiseguy who sidesteps society’s rules to live as he pleases.&lt;br&gt;He's torn between his well-hidden inhibitions and his artistic ambitions as a celebrated street photographer.&lt;br&gt;He's ashamed of his mother, Hanifa, for ignoring their aristocratic heritage - he isn't going to make that mistake.&lt;br&gt;Miranda is his wife, who desires him viscerally, but whom he more or less ignores because he feels she's beneath her. It's a marriage of convenience.&lt;br&gt;He and Suri were kidnapped and held in some basement for a time - he doesn't remember much save for the darkness, the blinding lights that sometimes broke that darkness, and the pain. Perhaps they've been experimented on, but what matters more is that he has been in love with Suri ever since. Suri is a coy tease, and apparently hasn't yet made up his mind about whether to enter into an affair - any way, it will end badly for Sebestyén, a fact he's blissfully unaware of.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h3&gt; Miranda&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="715" data-original-width="600" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S_3mFrSZfk0/XMRuKsNZnwI/AAAAAAAA1lg/ALhkBxHJHFMCg_SAYUjrhZ4k3drPHSH7QCLcBGAs/s320/miranda.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;div class="level__left"&gt;&lt;div class="level__item"&gt;&lt;div class="js-copy-attribute-content rd__p rd__p--no-margin"&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/@oleg-magni?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Oleg Magni&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/portrait-of-curly-haired-girl-918474/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels"&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;Whimsical New Age witch.&lt;br&gt;Recovered alcoholic, driven to suicide that Hanifa prevented, has been immensely grateful ever since, now that they've become business partners with her mother-in-law, she's not so sure.&lt;br&gt;What she wants more than anything is comfort and calm, but her life is still quite tumultuous, what with the husband who has eyes for the stunning and impassive bartender, and her coffee shop being taken over for spreading anti-establishment propaganda. I guess she's the sort of person who always wants to take charge of her life but relies on others too much to pull it off.&lt;br&gt;She's a bit taken aback by Suri's advances - does she really think she would be best buddies with the chick her husband wants to bang instead of her? When she stays faithful even when she could have any man (true, she does have a sort of magnetism)?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>faction</category><category>NPC</category><category>plot-hook</category><category>premise</category><category>traditionalist magick</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-batthyanyi-circle-traditionalist/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 16:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Cabal of the Monkey King - Traditionalist factions of Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl, part 3</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-cabal-of-monkey-king-traditionalist/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part three in a 4-part series of high-level overviews of the Traditionalist factions in my Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl campaign. See previous installments &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/the-schiffer-cabal-traditionalist.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/the-circle-collective-traditionalist.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cabal of the Monkey King&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-right: 1em; text-align: left; width: 100%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="534" data-original-width="800" src="https://fs.mingpao.com/ldy/20160116/s00008/c10f6774e1e71d84ae401b747c45ad9e.jpg" width="640"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Is he really the Monkey King?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Monkey King (Majomkirály &lt;span class="IPA"&gt;[ˈmɒjom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;&lt;span class="IPA"&gt;kiraːj&lt;/span&gt;] in the original Hungarian)&lt;/span&gt;, as he (or she?) calls themselves, is by far the most mysterious magickal inhabitant of the Budapest city state - no-one is really sure of his/her sex or gender. Every mage has heard of him/her, but there have been very few verified sightings. He/she spends most of their time in the Umbra, guarding &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/the-rudas-thermal-baths-location-npc.html"&gt;the Rudas Bath Horizon node&lt;/a&gt;, and, some say, the city as a whole from malevolent incursions. His name is, of course, not far from the lips of the thousands of Chinese descent living in Budapest - he is revered as a patron saint of sorts by the Chinese community, and might be a reason the minority isn't treated too badly by the otherwise quite nationalist council administration or the public.&lt;br&gt;In my game, he is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sun_Wukong"&gt;THE Sun Wukong&lt;/a&gt;, 'The Great Sage, Heaven's Equal', but I've limited his legendary abilities to the Near Umbra and beyond so as not unbalance the game - my players only met him once, and on Earth he's &lt;i&gt;just&lt;/i&gt; an immortal Akashic master:)&lt;br&gt;There is only one other member of his Budapest 'cabal' (he might have several others going on all over the world, who knows) is Hegedűs &lt;span class="IPA"&gt;[ˈhɛɡɛdyːʃ]&lt;/span&gt;, his real-world representative, an actual academic. She's a materials scientist shaman whose paradigm is that the Umbra isn't 'outer space' but the magnified microcosm of stuff - when she awakens objects' spirits (a popular pastime) and communes across the Gauntlet, she uses microscopes and heavy-duty magnifying glasses, and delves into the gap between the barbs of feathers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-right: 1em; text-align: left; width: 100%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="995" data-original-width="1024" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-QqZuaPWBCP4/XKE6Px-K9SI/AAAAAAAA1hE/4djFkgsHt78MYsvddElqiNtPBESIgOctQCLcBGAs/s320/hegedus.jpg" width="320"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Hegedűs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;The 'cabal' as such, then, doesn't really have a Budapest chantry, but Hegedűs can usually be reached at one of &lt;a href="http://egykor.hu/budapest-viii--kerulet/szazados-uti-muvesztelep/4007"&gt;the Százados Street Artist Colony&lt;/a&gt; houses - strictly for diplomatic business to be passed on to Majomkirály.&lt;br&gt;&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-right: 1em; text-align: left; width: 100%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" class="fitt" data-original-height="995" data-original-width="1024" src="https://www.magyarkurir.hu/img.php?id=79266&amp;amp;v=1&amp;amp;img=o_1_.jpg" width="320"&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;Those who need to know will recognize this place.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br&gt;</description><category>faction</category><category>NPC</category><category>premise</category><category>traditionalist magick</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/04/the-cabal-of-monkey-king-traditionalist/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 23:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Circle Collective  - Traditionalist factions in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-circle-collective-traditionalist/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part two in a 4-part series of high-level overviews of the main Traditionalist factions in my Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl campaign.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Circle Collective&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-right: 1em; text-align: left; width: 100%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://egykor.hu/images/2010/preview/budapest-ii-kerulet-hotel-budapest-korszallo-_6.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="407" data-original-width="240" height="640" src="https://egykor.hu/images/2010/preview/budapest-ii-kerulet-hotel-budapest-korszallo-_6.jpg" width="376"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1gu1mwT2TojgRMIBvrhwy-6zJV4L59s8X&amp;amp;usp=sharing"&gt;Hotel Budapest a.k.a the Circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Led by an Etherite, a former close associate of the Schiffer cabal's  leader, who has been estranged from his old friend but still maintains  an uneasy alliance with the Schiffer cabal.&lt;br&gt;So much so that the two  collectives actually share their primary headquarters - Villa Schiffer.&lt;br&gt;Given that the Circle Collective's ex-Iteration X-er, currently Etherite leader basically single-handedly invented the Quintessence-machine huffing and puffing in the Villa Schiffer basement, the two cabals are effectively stuck with each other no matter how the two groups' leaders feel.&lt;br&gt;Krausz, the group's head is ex-military, and defected from Iteration-X after a bungled Iraqi mission that got his beloved wife killed - he is adamant that the Convention had a hand in her death, and vowed revenge. He was all but adopted by the Schiffer cabal leader, who had been grooming him as his successor. But then &lt;span class="tootlip" title="A media blunder revealed that there are at least one clone of the Prime Minister. It took massive resources to frame it as an urban myth instead of proven fact."&gt;the Havassy-incident&lt;/span&gt; happened, and Krausz felt that his composer mentor's active role in the government cover-up was unconscionable&lt;br&gt;He has been recruiting his former cabal-mates from the Schiffer group with the promise of amassing 'a real Resistance movement', one that won't be afraid to rock the boat.&lt;br&gt;Although he did manage to convince a handful of mages, some in the newly minted collective suspect that 'the Resistance' will not amount to more than sitting around in the cabal's top-secret new chantry on the top floor of the Hotel Budapest, moping about Krausz's ex-wife, and cursing the Schiffer cabal leader.&lt;br&gt;Krausz might not be cut out to be a revolutionary, but his inventions are formidable, and his social network must be vast - he managed to kit out almost half the very top floor of &lt;a href="https://www.danubiushotels.com/en/our-hotels-budapest/hotel-budapest"&gt;the Hotel Budapest&lt;/a&gt; as a clandestine cabal headquarters with magickal detectors scanning as far as the river Danube. (At a safe distance from his former mentor's hideout.)</description><category>faction</category><category>NPC</category><category>premise</category><category>traditionalist magick</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-circle-collective-traditionalist/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 17:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Schiffer cabal - Traditionalist factions in Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl, part 1</title><link>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-schiffer-cabal-traditionalist/</link><dc:creator>Bujna Balázs</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is part one in a series of high-level overviews of the 4 main Traditionalist factions in my Mage: The Budapest Urbancrawl campaign.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="color: red;"&gt;Spoiler alert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;For those not playing with a collaborative world-building kind of troupe style, there might be some traditionally GM-only background material in this post.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Schiffer cabal&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-right: 1em; text-align: left; width: 100%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://6.kerulet.ittlakunk.hu/files/ittlakunk/styles/large/public/upload/event/6469/schiffer1.jpg?itok=fyhwvGWL&amp;amp;slideshow=true&amp;amp;slideshowAuto=true&amp;amp;slideshowSpeed=4000&amp;amp;speed=350&amp;amp;transition=none" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="544" data-original-width="800" height="433" src="https://6.kerulet.ittlakunk.hu/files/ittlakunk/styles/large/public/upload/event/6469/schiffer1.jpg?itok=fyhwvGWL&amp;amp;slideshow=true&amp;amp;slideshowAuto=true&amp;amp;slideshowSpeed=4000&amp;amp;speed=350&amp;amp;transition=none" width="640"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"&gt;The Schiffer villa, the cabal's headquarters&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;a name="more"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;A moderate '&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Realpolitik"&gt;Realpolitik&lt;/a&gt;' faction that is attempting a balancing act, forging compromises with both the Technocratic groups, the anti-magic city administration, and the more radical Traditionalist elements, be they native or visiting.&lt;br&gt;Their chantry is located very close to &lt;a href="https://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/2019/03/the-andrassy-rifts-magical-premise.html"&gt;the Andrássy Rifts&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=1gu1mwT2TojgRMIBvrhwy-6zJV4L59s8X&amp;amp;usp=sharing"&gt;19 Munkácsy Mihály street&lt;/a&gt; - the Schiffer villa that the collective takes its name from, which is &lt;a href="https://varosban.blog.hu/2017/09/13/titkos_budapesti_epuletek_schiffer-villa"&gt;a marvellous art deco palace on the inside, and a nondescript little museum building on the outside&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;The collective centres around a mechanical Node - essentially a big steam-engine style machine that manufactures Quintessence in an easy-to use solid form. The Node Machine is the invention of an Etherite who was until a recent major falling-out, best friends with the collective's Hermetic leader, and whose own cabal nominally still shares the chantry with the Schiffer group. The high-energy blocks are harvested by dedicated Enlightened and mundane engineers with a 24-7 rota, and distributed as a political favour among mages in the city.&lt;br&gt;The collective's apparent success at cautiously assertive diplomacy hinges on their leader, &lt;span class="tooltip" title="Who has, by all official accounts, been dead for the last 50 years!"&gt;a prestigious and world-famous Hungarian composer&lt;/span&gt;, who enjoys the full support and all the benefits of the worldwide Order of Hermes magical network.&lt;br&gt;They also have a non-Enlightened support network to call on - acolytes and servants who run and maintain the villa and the grounds, as well as civil rights NGOs (with non-Enlightened lawyers and activists who are sympathetic to the mystic cause) that are trying to help mages in the city by lobbying, offering legal counsel, and the like.&lt;br&gt;As might be expected, the collective is widely regarded as wishy-washy sellouts by other Enlightened folk, especially transient 'tourist mages' with no real understanding of local circumstances.</description><category>faction</category><category>premise</category><category>traditionalist magick</category><guid>http://budapest-urban-fantasy.blogspot.com/posts/2019/03/the-schiffer-cabal-traditionalist/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 14:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>